We just showed that because of
the intrinsic incompleteness
of models eliminating
bias in all dimensions
is mathematically impossible.
We could no doubt decrease
bias among some groups
to a certain degree, with an
acceptably small but still
significant margin of error.
Even if we got rid of bias in
some predefined dimensions,
we would still have it
in other dimensions.
But that's precisely it.
We want equality in at
least some dimensions,
the important ones.
That is good.
How do you choose which
dimensions are important?
Alvis.
One important
dimension is wealth.
Good.
So even you five, the
top engineering students
in your class at the top
engineering school, should get
paid just as much as someone
like Dean, the paper collector.
Well, he is a very nice
fellow, if a bit strange.
But no, we think we should be
rewarded for the contributions
that we make to society.
But wealth should be
distributed more equally.
That's right.
But how do you decide
how equal it should be?
Perhaps the problem
is once again
that mathematics in its
homogenization of kinds
is not the right way
to address the problem.
Let me ask you this--
is it really equality that
you want, or is it justice?
Justice.
Yeah.
I'll go with justice.
Great that you two
agree on something.
Glenda.
They should go hand in
hand, justice and equality.
Yeah.
Isn't equality justice?
I think we need to add
another consideration,
since we are beginning to
delve into the complex human
questions underlying
our definition
and perception of bias.
So let me ask you this.
Which is most important--
equality, justice,
or happiness?
Sophie.
I would say happiness.
Even if someone has
more than you do,
and even if they
don't deserve it,
it doesn't matter to you
as long as you are happy.
Think of all the people
born into rich families.
They're typically
not happy since they
don't need to have a goal, and
therefore they don't have one.
I would still have a goal if I
were born into a rich family.
Why do they need
a goal if they're
having such a good time?
Because people need to
have a purpose to be happy.
And how can people be happy
if they're not treated fairly?
So we have equality,
justice, and happiness,
but it is unclear which
is most important.
Glenda.
Can't they be of
equal importance?
Actually, no.
They are certainly interrelated.
But since they are at
least somewhat different
and since, as we saw, they
can conflict, one of them
has to be most important, has to
take precedence over the other.
I think that justice is more
important than equality.
After all, we don't want
everyone to be the exact same,
but still justice and
equality are related.
People can be unequal because
they're treated unfairly.
They can also be unequal
due to luck, good or bad.
I don't think that happiness
can be the standard.
We need equality, and that's
why mathematics is still
so important, because we
can employ it rigorously
to make everyone equal.
But if everyone is the same,
wouldn't the world be drab?
I mean, what if all
of us were the same?
We wouldn't even be able to
have this dialogue, as we'd all
be making the same point.
There would be
nothing interesting,
as everyone is reduced
to a forced homogeneity.
Besides, how do
you make everyone
equal without
violating their rights?
We're going to have to
violate some rights to make
people at least more equal.
But then maybe I guess
that's not justice.
Yeah.
Isn't it the essence of tyranny
when rights are violated
in the name of justice?
Yes.
We have strong reasons
not to want that.
We want equality,
but we certainly
don't want to violate
people's rights to get it.
But what do we do?
Here we are at an impasse again.
How do we understand
this conflict
between equality and rights?
By the way, professor,
what about that other way
that you promised?